Jack: So, let’s have a look at
Scrum Events in a little more
detail, starting with ‘The Sprint’
Leah: The sprint is a fixed length
event which has a sprint goal.
All events are time-boxed so once
a sprint begins, it is fixed.
The sprint itself, involves a collection
of ‘tasks’ for the team to achieve.
Each task or ‘user story’ is
allocated a level of complexity
called a ‘story point’.
A sprint project board which is also
known as the ‘Sprint Backlog’ is used
to track the tasks, and sub-tasks
are positioned in three columns - ‘To
do’, ‘In progress’, and ‘Done’.
Jack: Sprint planning is the
first meeting of the sprint.
It is where achievable items or user
stories, are identified from the product
backlog to be moved to the next sprint.
The team would decide in this meeting,
what can be done within the next
sprint, and then refine the user
stories; for example, they would
determine story-points, how tasks
will get done, the definition of
done, dependencies, and sub-tasks.
The Scrum Master who ensures that
the framework is followed, would
predominately manage this meeting, taking
into consideration priority, capacity,
and the wider business expectations.
However, before this meeting can
take place, the Product Owner would
need to determine the priority
tasks and decide on the sprint goal.
Team members would also need to allocate
their own tasks on the product backlog.
Leah: The Daily Scrum, also known as
the ‘Daily Standup’, is a 15 minute
meeting for the internal scrum team,
which is arranged at the same time,
each working day of the sprint.
Its main objective is to determine
progress and update the project board,
also known as the ‘sprint backlog’, and
adapt the ‘product backlog’ if needed.
The focus is on progress and actions, and
self-management is encouraged, as well
as promoting collaboration, improvement,
and transparency amongst team members.
It is ‘not’ meant to be a ‘status’
meeting but is meant to be about
achieving valuable outcomes.
It is also supposed to eliminate
the need for other meetings,
improve communication and
decision-making, and identify blockers.
Jack: The Sprint Review is where the scrum
team present their results from the work
they have done in the current sprint, to
the stakeholders and/or the customers.
It is where feedback is given, and
adaptations, alterations, changes and
or improvements can be planned for.
The sprint review is a working session,
not just a presentation and the
product backlog is adjusted to reflect
new information and or feedback.
It is usually one of the
last events of the sprint.
Leah: The Sprint Retrospective or retro is
the last meeting and concludes the sprint.
This is where the team determine what went
well, what could be improved, what needs
greater understanding, and the actions
that need to be taken, moving forward.
The retro is a safe place where
the team can come together, give
support and productive feedback.
The purpose of the retro is to act on
what has been reviewed, and plan ways
to increase quality and effectiveness.
One of the biggest benefits of
working in Agile is ‘continuous
improvement’, and in Scrum the driver
of improvement is the ‘Retrospective’.
Jack: You can hear more about Agile
and Scrum and what it’s like to be
a Scrum Master in the video below.